<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="28"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Course
                                                                       C      o      u      r   s     e







                                                                                                     :

                                                                                                     :
                                                                                                        2

                                                                                          P
                                                                                          Part  2
                                                                                             a
                                                                                                 t
                                                                                                r]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Welcome back, Game designers!


                 Are you ready to take a new step


                 into the world of game  creation






            Do you remember what we do here? Yes, we use Roblox Studio to


            make the games ourselves. This program helps us create and



            modify the game world in a very easy and simple way, as we saw


            last time



            Now, let's learn more about how to build more difficult things.


            Let's start building our first game today!






                                                                                    Let’s start working



                     Open Roblox Studio.


                     Choose the "Baseplate" template to start creating


             Note: Baseplate is an empty world that we can create whatever


             we want inside, so we'll select it to start




















                                                                                                          2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Now your world will open with you and we will be ready to start


             building our first world. Let's start creating !










































                         "Can you remember what shows up in this  workspace?"






































                                                                                                          3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[We explained last time that the workspace in Roblox consists of 5


             menus that we will constantly learn. Now, type the name of each


             list.

                                                                                                        1



                                                                                                       2




                                                                                                       3


                                                                                                       4




                                                                                                       5




             "If  you  don't  remember,  quickly  check  the  previous  lecture,  as


             we'll use it today."








                                                                                    let’s start building





             Any  structure  consists  of  main  components,  and  when



             assembled, we can build any shape we want. These components


             are:


                     Block


                     sphere











                                                                                                          4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[cylinder


                     wedge











             We  can  easily  find  those  components  in  Roblox  to  draw  them


             within the Model menu in the Toolbox.
















                                       Look inside Parts, you will find all the parts we


                                       talked about. You can click on the item you


                                       want and move it into the workspace to start


                                       building













                                                              Now  that  we've  placed  some


                                                              components, we want to adjust


                                                              them  to  create  more  complex


                                                              shapes.








                                                                                                          5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Inside the Model menu, there are several options to control and


             modify the parts. These options are:






                                                Move: Move parts to any desired location






                                                           Scale: Change the size of the parts







                                             Rotate: Rotate the parts at different angles






             Using these tools helps us build and modify parts easily, enabling


             us to create complex and creative shapes












































                                                                                                          6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[MOVE:


             This  allows  us  to  change  the  position  of  objects  in  your


             workspace.


                     There are 6 arrows extending from the part, Indicating 6


                     directions of movement.



                     Drag the arrows to move the part in the indicated direction.
























             SCALE:


             This tool allows us to adjust the size of blocks and shapes.


                     When you click on it, 6 circles appear around the part.


                     Click and drag a circle with the left mouse button to resize



                     the part.






















                                                                                                          7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Rotate:


                     This  tool  allows  us  to  rotate  objects,  giving  them  a  new


                     direction to enhance our designs.


                     Three circles will appear around the part. Drag one of them



                     to .rotate the part.











































                                                  You can also modify the steps from here.






















                                                                                                          8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[If  you  place  a  part  by  mistake  and


                                                          want to delete it


                                                            you  can  simply  remove  unwanted

                                                          parts by selecting them and pressing


                                                          the delete button


                                                           Alternatively, you can right-click on

                                                          the  item  and  choose  the  delete


                                                          command
























              It's important for you to gain experience using each tool, so give


              them a try yourself.




              Shortcuts:


                      You can move parts by grabbing them from the centre, and



                      in this case, the Z position will automatically adjust to the


                      top of the ground.


                       If you want to zoom in on a specific bloc k, select it


                      and click "F"


                                                                                                         9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Property Adjustment:


              Now it's time to adjust properties such as color, material, and


              some physical characteristics of the placed parts






                                                                  All you need to do is choose


                                                                  the  item  you  want  by



                                                                  making  sure  the  "Select"


                                                                  command is chosen.






              Then click on the item you want. You will see the item's properties


              appear, and you can start changing them.










































                                                                                                          10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Let's explore some of the properties we can modify:











































           1. Brick Color:


           To change the color of the part, find the "Brick Color" property in


           the properties window


           Choose the color you want from the available list





























                                                                                                          11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[2.Color:


             To change the color using the "Color" property, which will give


             you more options

























            3. Cast Shadow:


            Choose whether the item has a shadow by enabling or disabling


            the property














































                                                                                                          12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[4.Material:


              .Change the item's material to change its appearance


             Choose from options like plastic, wood, or stone to give items a


             unique and realistic look. Enjoy experimenting with these options





































                Transparency:

                To change the transparency of the item, adjust the transparency


                value between 0 (fully opaque) and 1 (fully transparent) using the

                scrollbar or by manually entering the value


























                                                                                                          13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Anchored:


                                                  And here's the most important


                                                  property! In Roblox, objects are affected


                                                  by physics like gravity. Choosing


                                                  "Anchored" makes them unaffected


                                                  and remain fixed in place under all


                                                  circumstances






             You  can  lift  an  object  upward  and  test  the  game  with  the


             "Anchored" property on and off to see how it behaves differently.


             Notice how the object stays still when the property is on, and how


             it falls and responds to gravity when it's off.










































                                                                                                          14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Now let's try to create more advanced parts using these basic


             shapes! For example, let's build a tree like this:





































             Let's take a more simple look at the tree:


             Notice of how the tree is built from a tall brown cylinder with a


             large green sphere atop it that is decorated with smaller green


             spheres





























                                                                                                          15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Now, simply follow these steps:


             1.To start, drag the cylinder shape from the panel and position it


             appropriately.


             2.Resize it to match the tree trunk's shape.


             3. Choose the sphere shape from the parts and position it on top of


             the cylinder.



             4.Add small spheres around the large sphere to represent leaves.


             5.Make sure to adjust the properties of the cylinder, large sphere,


             and small spheres using the properties window.


             6.Remember to activate the "Anchored" property for all parts to


             keep the tree stable and prevent it from falling.











































                                                                                                          16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Now let's build our first game!




              In this game, you need to jump over obstacles to reach the finish


              final point without harm.






































            A  quick  look  at  the  game  reveals  it's  composed  of  blocks  and


            shapes with adjusted properties.






























                                                                                                          17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Steps to build the game:

                                                  1.Let's place the first part in the game, which is


                                                  a simple block with its color and material

                                                  changed


                                                         Note: Make sure to adjust the height of


                                                         the part to be suitable for jumping

























             2.  Repeat  the  same  step  twice  to  create

             additional obstacles .

                    You can either place new blocks or

                    use a simpler method, such as using
                    the Ctrl+D shortcut to duplicate the

                    shape and then adjust its position

                    and size























                                                                                                          18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Now let's try what we've achieved.

































                                                                Now  it's  time  for  the  flying


                                                                obstacles, which consist of 4

                                                                blocks  raised  upwards  with

                                                                their properties modified.


                                                                        Don't forget to set them

                                                                        as Anchored to prevent

                                                                        them from falling.































                                                                                                          19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Now  repeat  the  process  using  the  shortcut  Ctrl+D  to  create  3


             more blocks.



























             Now, place the large part, which is



             just a block, and change its color and


             material.









































                                                                                                          20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Now, as this part is quite elevated,


                                                        let's create an ascending pathway


                                                        by placing a wedge.








































                                                         Now let's try what we've achieved.
































                                                                                                          21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Now,  how  about  adding  some


                                                                  fun by including some balls for


                                                                  the  player  to  play  with  while


                                                                  running?





























         Now,  let's  build  this  unusual  shape.  Don't



         worry about its appearance, as it's simply


         two  cylinders  of  different  sizes  merged


         together.



























                                                                                                          22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Place the last piece now, which is the final block. I'm sure that building it will be


     easy for you.




































           To this point, this is the result.












































                                                                                                          23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Toolbox:


       Now we've reached this point and successfully built all of this


       But what about placing a bridge between the obstacles?
























             Building  the  bridge  might  seem  simple,  but  it  does  take  time.


             That's  where  Roblox's  Toolbox  becomes  useful.  It's  like  magic!


             Through it, we can find pre-made objects ready to use.











































                                                                                                          24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Using the Toolbox to add a bridge:


                                                           1. Open  the  Toolbox:  Make  sure  you


                                                             have  the  Toolbox  open.  If  it's  not

                                                             open, you can open it from the View


                                                             menu and selecting Toolbox.


                                                          2.  Search for a bridge:


                                                             Type “Bridge” in the search bar and


                                                             press Enter.


                                                          3. Select the bridge:


                                                             Drag  the  bridge  and  place  it  in  a


                                                             suitable  location  between  the


                                                             obstacles  in  the  game  path.in  the


                                                             game path.


                                                          4. Adjust the bridge:


           Use editing tools (such as moving, rotating, and scaling) to adjust the


           bridge to fit the game design. Ensure to modify the properties of the


           bridge and make it Anchored to keep it stable in its place.
























                                                                                                          25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[To change the sky:


                                                                 simply search for "Sky" in the Tool


                                                                 Box and drag the one you prefer.



























                                                                    Now, here is the final result:








































                                                         You  can  download  it  to  try  it  out


                                                         and see it from here.



                                                                                                          26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Let's play!



           Game: Dream Pet Connect


           Connect the same animals in this Dream Pet Connect game. The

           connection path cannot change directions more than twice.









































































                                                                                                          27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[For STEAM

                      Education Solutions





                                                                                            Course
                                                                                            C o  u  r s e

                                                                                                      t
                                                                                                     r
                                                                                                    a
                                                                                                        2


                                                                                                   P
                                                                                                   Part  2



























































                                                                        Alexandria:
                                                                        Elwezarah, 509 Abu Qir St. 3rd floor
                 0122 001 6331
                                                                        Cairo:
                 info@pyramakerz.com                                    40 Ahmed Fakhry St. Nasr City]]></page></pages></Search>
