<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="14"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT









         Introduction:


         This session focuses on building a simple web page and linking
         multiple pages together. In addition to, introducing CSS classes

         and property applying priority.
























                                                               Learning Outcomes:






                                                                .  1 CSS Classes.


                                                               2 .  Page Linking.


                                                               3 .  Integrating Images.


























                                                                                                              2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT









         CSS Classes:


         CSS classes are a way to group HTML elements that you want to style in a similar
         way. By defining a class in CSS, you can apply the same styles to multiple elements

         without needing to style each one individually.









                                                                           You can give your
                                                                           styles a name.




























           In  the  css  file,  classes
           should  have  a  period  “.”

           before  the  name




















         3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT









         You can add multiple classes to the same element. The last class written is the one
         who has more priority when having 2 classes that edit the same property.








                                                                                The class attribute

                                                                                allows you to put
                                                                                multiple classes.




























                               This gets ignored.






                               This gets applied.






















                                                                                                              4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT









         Page Linking:


         If we have 2 pages like these, how to connect them that we can navigate from “index.
         html” to “coffee_menu.html”?














         In the anchor tags, we place the file name in the href attribute.














         Project: Cafe Store.



         Goal is to build a cafe page with pages linked to each other like this:


































         5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT









         Let’s begin with analyzing the page:




           •  Page color: #F8F4F1
           •  We have a section with width and border.
           •  Text color: 828282#
           •  Anchor links color: #D97628
           •  There are paddings and margins.




















         Set up the HTML file and link it with a CSS file:









































                                                                                                              6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT













































         Now to the main body:



         use the coffee image to place it in the body using <img> tag and add some margin in
         the css file.


































         7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT


























           •  Margin:
                 •  10 px from the top
                 •  350px from right & left
                 •  0 px from the bottom
           •  border-radius: to make round corners:
                 •  %50 means make a circle frame around the image.
           •  border: to give the frame a border of 2px thick.



         Result:











































                                                                                                              8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT









         Let’s add some text to give the user some information about the cafe store.


















































         •  We added a title using <h1> tag, a paragraph <p> for description, and an unordered
            list for the list of items the cafe has.


         •  Styling them with CSS gives us the following result:



















         9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT









         Page Linking:




         •  The cafe has 2 menus, let’s put each menu in its separate page.
         •  Add the following text into your html.




























         •  Copy index.html file twice and rename the files to:


           •  coffee_menu.html
           •  chocolate_menu.html

































                                                                                                              10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT









         Chocolate Menu File:



         •  The theme of both pages are the same as our home page “index.html” file.
         •  We only have to edit the inner text content to display the menus.































         Coffee Menu File:




         •  Same with the coffee menu file.































        11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT









         •  Great, now open the home page and try to click on either links. You’ll be switched
            to the corresponding menu page.


























         •  Chocolate page.
























                                            •  Coffee page:





















                                                                                                              12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Web


           Web                                                                                                                 DEVELOPMENT







           DEVELOPMENT













































































                                                                                ALEXANDRIA:
                                                0122 001 6331                   ELWEZARAH, 509 ABU QIR ST. 3RD FLOOR
                                                                                CAIRO:
                                                INFO@PYRAMAKERZ.COM             40 AHMED FAKHRY ST. NASR CITY]]></page></pages></Search>