<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="15"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT









         Display in CSS:


         The display property is used to specify how an element is shown on a web page.
         Every  HTML  element  has  a  default  display  value,  depending  on  what  type  of

         element it is. The default display value for most elements is block or inline .

         Block Display:



         Displays an element as a block element (like <p>). It starts on a new line, and
         takes up the whole width.



         Example:





















































                                                                                                              2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT









           Inline Display:


           The display option of inline tells the element to fit itself on the same line.





           Example:


































































         3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT







         Flex Display:


         The display option allows you to create flexible layouts

         with elements that you can align and distribute
         vertically  or  horizontally.













































                                                            At first, It may look as inline display.























                                                                                                              4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT







         Flex box gives us the some tools to use to better align items

         justify-content:



         It helps us align items on the x-axis of the container.
















































         space-around





















         5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT






         Other values can also be used:





            space-around








           space-between








                center






         align-items:



         It helps us align items on the y-axis of the
         container.






































                                                                                                              6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT






         Note: You can combine justify-content & align-items to make custom layouts and
         awesome ordering.
























         Other values can also be used:



                                 Start                                            End




















                                Center                                          Stretch

























         7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT







         Project: Store 102:


         Let’s practice the use of display layouts and build a more appealing store like this:































          Let’s break the page into smaller parts:




         Flex Header








                                                                                         padding








                          Flex Footer
















                                                                                                              8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT







         Solution:


         First, Build the navbar.











































































         9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT




         Result:










         That’s one part done:


         •  Built a navbar using <nav> semantic tag.
         •  Inserted an image and a list with some links inside it.
         •  We set the <nav> to display as flex and set its inner elements to be distribute on
            x-axis using “justify-content: space-around;”.

         •  We get to know about a new CSS property:
            •  list-style: none;
            •  This lets us remove bullets or numbers from the lists.
         •  We also added some padding to the list items to make it more appealing to the
            eyes.










         Now to the main body:








                                                               break <br>
                                                   Used to add a new line within
                                                             the same tag























                                                                                                              10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT


































         Result:





         That’s one part done:


         •  Built another semantic area <section> to welcome our users, and invite them to
            view our products
         •  We also placed an image for decoration and grouped both elements inside a flex
            element that aligns the elements on the center of x-axis.



































        11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Web


       DEVELOPMENT








         Finally, the footer:














































































                                                                                                              12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Web


                                                                                         DEVELOPMENT








         Result:






































         Finally:


         •  Built the last semantic area <footer> to display our contact number
         •  we also used “align-items:center;” to align our paragraph tag to the center of
            y-axis of the footer.






























        13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Web


           Web                                                                                                                 DEVELOPMENT







           DEVELOPMENT













































































                                                                                ALEXANDRIA:
                                                0122 001 6331                   ELWEZARAH, 509 ABU QIR ST. 3RD FLOOR
                                                                                CAIRO:
                                                INFO@PYRAMAKERZ.COM             40 AHMED FAKHRY ST. NASR CITY]]></page><page Index="15"/></pages></Search>
